Contact

sruths33@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/sruthspr (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Brand Management
Corporate Communications
Public Relations

Languages

Telugu (Limited Working)

Tamil (Limited Working)

English (Professional Working)

Sruthi Chandrasekhar

Consultant - Paid Social Media & Brand Management Chennai

Summary

Sruthi is currently working as an Consultant - Social Media & Brand Management for Interactive Avenues. The company is backed by IPG Mediabrands.

Previously, she was working as an Assistant Brand Manager in a publishing company called Vikatan Group looking into brand management and corporate communications. Sruthi had worked with clients across various fields like entertainment, automobile, printing & publication, consumer durables, cement manufacturing, logistics, hospitality, etc.

There is a strong base in the media field considering her U.G degree was in Journalism and Visual Communication. There were a series of internships in media houses like Raj Televisions Network, Hello FM, Jupiter Communications, NDTV Hindu and Maximum Media.

As a part of her extra-curricular activities, she loves watching movies, organic gardening and is an upcoming social media influencer.

Experience

Interactive Avenues
Consultant - Paid Social Media & Brand Management
July 2020 - Present (9 months)
Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

Digital Marketing - Paid Social Media

- Managing the Social Media Pages / Channels/ Handles of clients.
- Paid Social campaign strategy implementation.
- Understand the client's product and their brand marketing objectives and goals.
- Review and analyse competitor Social handles.

- Define a campaign strategy and deliverable plans that exceed client expectations.
- Work closely with other internal departments to develop fully integrated social media campaigns.
- Attend client meetings to present deliverables, campaign strategies, tactics.
- Deliver monthly client reports, verify data accuracy, provide analysis; to keep clients updated on account status.
- Support the Director in data acquisition or campaign insights for quarterly or annual business reviews.
- Stay current on industry trends & standard methodologies and present practical ideas for future marketing optimization.
- Think creatively and develop SOPs & tactics to improve efficiencies.

Brand Management & Corporate Communications

- Create & deliver company literature, marketing, promotional materials like brochures, press release, corporate newsletters as appropriate at opportune occasions.
- Verify, edit, proofread & revise communications before being sent to relevant output medium.
- Coordinate with relevant departments & advertising agencies for delivering timely & appropriate brand marketing material.
- Assist creative and marketing departments in launching marketing campaigns.
- Propose recommendations to implement & maintain corporate website.
- Independently take branding & corporate communication initiatives.
- Align & drive initiatives in line with the corporate brand standard with the quarterly marketing calendar & regional marketing strategy to ensure successful & consistent brand experience.
- Implement regional & marketing activities, brand collateral, events, marketing & communication as part of the larger brand campaigns and sub-regional account initiatives.

Vikatan

Assistant Brand Manager Marketing October 2019 - June 2020 (9 months)

Chennai Area, India

- Experience of handling social media related software and tools.
- Publish contents on different social media channels to build brand presence.
- Experienced content writer.

- Ability to research and think of new ideas and implement those ideas into a reality.
- TG specific campaigns for increasing brand awareness.
- Create and manage content across platforms such as websites, social media channels, marketing collaterals etc.
- Create social media content strategy and develop content accordingly.
- . Create brand management calendar and develop and execute content accordingly.

Fox Creatives

Brand Consultant

October 2017 - October 2019 (2 years 1 month)

Chennai

Corporate Communications, Content Management, Brand Management & Event Management

The KCP Limited

Executive - Corporate Communications

June 2016 - September 2017 (1 year 4 months)

Chennai Area, India

Corporate Communications, Content Management, Brand Management & Event Management

Mathangi Enterprises
Executive - PR & Events
May 2011 - May 2016 (5 years 1 month)

Chennai Area, India

Public Relations & Event Management

Education

D.G. Vaishnav College

Bachelor's Degree, Design and Visual Communications,

General · (2008 - 2011)